# Adam Whitehurst

## Web Developer

(631) 833 4854 - awhitehurst 4@gmail.com Washington, DC

Portfolio – nairul.github.io/portfolio Github – github.com/nairul LinkedIn – linkedin.com/in/adam-whitehurst

Effective collaborator and liaison between clients and developers. I specialize in front-end design with experience in making accessible and interactive sites.

#### SKILLS

**S of t ware**: React, Angular, Mongo, Express, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Ruby, Rails, SQL, ActiveRecord, Postgres

Applications: Hootsuite, Wordpress, Trello

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Web Editor**: American University, College of Arts and Sciences (Washington, DC), 2015 – present

Edited and curated College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) website content and page organization for over 50 degree programs and 13 research centers

Created new website pages and create new content for various CAS departments, centers, and administrative offices, including <a href="https://example.com/status-new-content-status-new-content-status-new-content-status-new-content-status-new-center-status-new-content-status-new-center-status-new-cent

Increased CAS web accessibility, readability, and interactivity through use of data analysis from Google Analytics and other best-practices university web guides

Web Development Immersive Student: General Assembly (Washington, DC), 2017

Participated in rigorous 12-week instructional program at General Assembly's Washington, DC campus. Learned necessary technologies and acquired skills for web development

Completed four major projects, including a password manager web application in Ruby on Rails <u>smartuser.herokuapp.com</u>

Intern: Smithsonian National Museum of American History (Washington, DC), 2012 – 2013

Authored and curated "<u>Today in Jazz History</u>" project to advance-schedule over 1,000 tweets using Hootsuite social media platform

**Research Assistant**: Center of Excellence in Wireless and Information Technology (CEWIT) (Stony Brook, NY), 2012

Researched and compiled latest innovations in wireless biomedicine field and presented to Director of the Medical Technologies Division for potential collaborative opportunities

Collaborated with web development team to design CEWIT conference website

#### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly: Washington, DC, Web Development Immersive, 2017

American University: Washington, DC, History PhD, 2014 – 2017

Completed regular coursework, dissertation remaining.

Trinity College: Hartford, CT, Bachelor of Arts, 2008 – 2012

Awarded the D. G. Brinton Thompson Prize in the study of United States History Faculty Honors, Spring 2009-2010, 2012